Brian Salehi

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Brian Salehi

Software Engineer

Professional Summary I am a Linux system programmer, having experience in C and C++ programming and using a few scripting languages and development tools. I am interested in open source movement, and I usually spend some of my spare time making open source tools or contributing to open source projects.

Fields of Expertise

Linux System Programming

Linux applications and services

User Interface Development

Designing desktop user interface using Qt framework

Fields of Studies

Image Processing

Using OpenCV library to process images and videos

Graphics Programming

Creating 3D graphics scene using OpenGL APIs

Experiences

Arad Research and Development Company

aradtechs.com

Software Engineer

05/2021 - present

Updated: April 12, 2022

Contributed to many projects in a professional team from programming desktop applications, designing user interfaces, programming 3D graphical applications and web services to documenting each of these projects extensively.

Training milextone.ir

Software Engineer, Technical Trainer

03/2019 - 03/2021

I had 11 students from freshman year of college to PhD candidate in Iran, Germany and Poland, teaching programming and administration.

Manzoomeh Negaran Holdings

seller.ir

Software Engineer, Database Specialist

06/2016 - 06/2017

Designed, implemented and maintained the back-end and database services of an industrial webstore.

Cooperations

Bioengineering Laboratory

Poland (undisclosed)

Software Engineer

08/2020 - present

Consulting technical solutions for development of computational services.

Sarmad Business Services Company

Iran (*sarmadbs.com*)

System Administrator, Database Specialist

04/2021 - 06/2021

Consulting technical solutions to maintain systems and services.

Brian Salehi

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Skills

Technical Skills

C++

Writing programs using STL and Boost with recent language standards

C

Linux interface programming and developing high performance services

Python

Advanced scripting, prototyping, and automating with unit tests

x86 64 Assembly

Writing processor specific high performance procedures and data vectorization

Qt, QML, JavaScript

Developing full-featured cross-platform graphical user interfaces

Bash

Advanced scripting, prototyping and automating in Linux systems

Linux Administration

Configuring, automating, administering and securing Linux systems

PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Designing, developing and administering relational and non-relational databases

Tools

Git

Taking advantage of advanced Git usage and variety of development workflows

GCC, GDB, Valgrind

Using compiling optimizations, debugging techniques, and memory checking

Make, CMake Suite

Adapting projects to auto-compiling, testing, packaging and monitoring

Doxygen, UML, PlantUML

Writing precise tutorial like documentations containing UML diagrams

CI/CD Tools

Storing, maintaining, testing and documenting code base in CI/CD tools

Miscellaneous Skills

Vim

My default text editor for coding and configuring

LaTeX

Writing documents, specially this resume

Brian Salehi

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Education

Islamic Azad University, Tehran North

MSc. of Computer Science, Software Engineering 09/2021 - 06/2023

Islamic Azad University, Tehran East

iauet.ac.ir

BSc. of Computer Science 09/2016 - 06/2021

Certificates

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

Embedded Linux 5/2021 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

Linux Application Development 5/2021 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir LPIC-3: Linux Security 3/2017 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

LPIC-2: Linux Networks 3/2016 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

LPIC-1: Linux Systems 3/2015 - present

Interests

Technical

Image processing, machine learning, graphics programming, user interfaces, kernel hacking, embedded Linux, software and hardware design, algorithms, mathematics, quantum mechanics, philosophy, psychiatry

Personal

Playing electric guitar, reading books, swimming, biking, running, hiking

Languages

English Fluent

I have a strong studying background in English.

German Basic

I'm currently learning German to the extent of working in Germany.

References

Dr. Farhang Jaryani

fjayani@yahoo.com

Faculty of Computer Science, Arak University, Iran